# **SAMREEN KARIM**

# Software Engineer | Full Stack Developer



iamsamreenk@gmail.com

Express Highway Garden Town near Khanapul, Islamabad

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ samreen-karim-7178a5220/

https://github.com/samreen32/

https://samreenkarimportfolio.netlify.app/

# **KEY SKILLS**

Front-end Web UI framework & tools

Git (push pull requests, commits)

JavaScript, Material UI, Bootstrap

React JS, React Native

REST API, Express, Node, PHP,

MongoDB

Multi-Tasking, Problem Solving,

Client Handling, Task Handling.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **BS / Software Engineering**

NUML, Islamabad 2019 - 2023 CGPA 3.4

#### **FSC / Pre-Engineering**

IMCG F-7/4 Margalla, Islamabad 2017 – 2019 Grade A

#### Matric / Science

IMSG F-7/2, Islamabad 2015 – 2019 Grade A+

#### **AWARDS**

# NGIRI Ignite Wining for Final Year Project (FYP)

HEC, Pakistan 2023

# ABOUT ME

I am a recent graduate with a Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering, having 1 year of experience in designing and building Web and Mobile Applications. I have completed my Final Year Project that aims to address the problem of parking through a React Native application, using Express, Node JS, MongoDB and Figma for an application design and UI. With my hands-on experience in both front-end and back-end development, I am well-equipped to contribute to an organization's growth and success.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER (Onsite)**

Codrivity, I-8 Markaz Islamabad / May 2023 - Present

- Utilizing my expertise in web development, working in React JS, Shopify, and API Integration from Django backend.
- Complete project in React JS while integrating endpoints from backend.
- Negotiation with backend team, customize endpoints and develop an appealing product.
- Handle international clients while maintaining effective communication.
- I continue to expand my skill set by learning web scraping techniques.
- I learned to work within deadlines and enhance my leadership skills.

#### FRONT & BACKEND DEVELOPER - Intern (Remote)

BOT Solutions / Dec 2022 - Feb 2023

- "E-Installment Application" Completed responsive application in PHP, MySQL as a backend database and Bootstrap, HTML, CSS and JavaScript for application design.
- "Customer-Developer Relation" MERN stack application using MongoDB as the backend database using Express and Node JS on the server.
- I learned to work in different frameworks, and increase my skill set.
- Strengthened team-building skills, enabling effective collaboration within a team
- Enhanced time management skills.

#### **DEVELOPER**

Self-Projects / Sep 2022 - Present

✓ E-Parking Challan App / FYP (April 2022 – Sep 2023)

Developed a mobile application using React Native, employing Express, Node JS, and MongoDB Atlas.

I learned to develop a mobile application while working on both frontend & backend.

✓ Coffee Shop MERN Application (Nov 2022 – Dec 2022)

Developed a responsive MERN stack application for coffee selling shop, as a semester project.

I learned to design responsive website using ReactJS, Express, and NodeJS and successfully deployed an application on GitHub.

✓ Flower Selling Responsive Website (Sep 2022 – Oct 2022)

Developed a responsive website for flower selling shop as my semester project using pure HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.

I learned to design responsive website using pure HTML, CSS, JS, and PHP.